# María José Márquez Pérez

I'm a Frontend Developer passionate for technology, design and development looking to expand my current skillset while contributing in innovative and high-impact projects.

After many years working in different industries, I found my passion in technology and decided to take the leap forward. I love change and working with other inspiring professionals.



**SKILLS** 

#### **Frontend Dev**

HTML, CSS, JS, React, Redux.

#### **Software Dev**

Git, Node JS, Firebase.

## Web Design

Figma, Photoshop, Bootstrap.

#### **Soft Skills**

Scrum project management, sales management, team building, team leading.



**SOME POJECTS** 

In Progress



**LANGUAGES** 

Spanish (Native) English (Intermediate)



**HOBBIES** 

My hobbies are decorating, creating and recycling furniture, camping, meditation, listening to music and watching movies.



## **EDUCATION**

Frontend Developer 2009 – Present Bootcamp Laboratoria

In Laboratoria besides knowing the programming languages I have learned about teamwork and its importance developing technical skills and soft skills. I chose the frontend development area, where I also obtained knowledge of UX / UI, using agile methodologies and self-learning.

Veterinary Medicine 2005 – 2010 Universidad Pedro de Valdivia.

**Civil Engineering specializing in Structures** 2000 – 2003 Universidad Central.



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Entrepreneurship 2017-2018

Sale and recycling of medical clothing.

Executive Sales and Customer Service 06/2016 – 2017 LAN Airlines Customer service and Sales in LAN airline, helping passengers in the selection of tours and other needs for their trips, solution of incidents and changes of tickets.

**Veterinarian** 02/2014 – 05/2016 Clinical Helkekura Primary health care for pets, treatments and disease prevention.

**Food Technology** 06/2012 – 01/2014 Unimarc

Responsible for training and monitoring staff in good food practices. Enforce the HACCP requirements and Sanitary and Hygiene Regulations.

**Development of Zoonoses projects** 03/2005 - 02/2011 I.M. de Cerrillos. Creation and development of responsible pet ownership projects, responsible pet ownership and native fauna classes in municipal schools and neighborhood groups belonging to the area, promotion of sterilizations and vaccines, pest control and pet census.



# **VOLUNTEERING**

**Assistant professor** 2007 – 2009 U. Iberoamericana.

Mathematics and chemistry classes

**Tutor** 2008 – 2011 Preujoven.

Physics, math and biology classes.

Phone: +56939356644 Email: majomarquez@gmail.com Address: Santiago, Chile

Portfolio: GitHub: